

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER/PHYSICIST

Oslo, Norway

□ (+47) 415 14 840 | weirikma@gmail.com | meirik-marthinsen | meirik-marthinsen

Father, husband, hobby skier and passionate software developer

Summary_

Physicist/software developer with over 10 years experience. Mainly developing multiphysics simulation tools used in the oil and gas industry for simulating fire and fire response on process equipment. Responsible for building, testing, automation (DevOps), code analysis as well as implementing mathematical models.

Using C++ as my main language, and Python for supporting libraries and small tasks.

Passion for technology, with broad range of technical skills, long experience. I'm patient and like to work on hard problems. I'm focused on details and seldom give up before I'm satisfied with my work. As a colleague I'm nice and positive and hard working.

Skills____

Programming C/C++ • Python • Rust • LTFX• Bash

Techical skills Git • Docker • Linux • Windows • Jenkins • Visual Studio

Languages Norwegian (native) • English (fluent)

Projects_____

Brilliant / VessFire (C++)

Petrell, etc

DEVELOPMENT OF INHOUSE MULTIPHYSICS (CFD++) SIMULATION ENGINE

2012 - Present

- Adding features, thermodynamic models, command parsing, binary result file IO, +++
- Responsible for testing, automation (Jenkins) and build system etc.
- Modernizing legacy C++ code to modern safe and performant C++20 code (Clang-Tidy, etc)
- Implementing new license system with OAuth2 using cpprestsdk
- Cross platform Windows and Linux, compiling with Intel, MSVC, GCC and Clang
- C++ libraries Eigen/MKL, Sqlite, CppRestSDK, SQLite, Curl, GoogleTest
- Using tools like Visual Studio, Clang-Tidy, Clang-Format, Valgrind, address/UB sanitizers

PvBrf (Pvthon)

Petrell, etc.

PYTHON PACKAGE WITH MULUTIPLE COMMAND LINE TOOLS FOR BRILLIANT SIMULATIONS

AND RESULT ANALYSIS

2018 - Present

- Binary result file parser using numpy to store large data sets
- Using modern Python 3.6
- Extensively tested with PyTest
- Ensure high code quality with pylint type hints and MyPy

BrilliantGUI / VessFireGUI (Qt/C++)

Petrell, etc.

DEVELOPMENT OF SIMULATION CASE EDITOR AND RESULT VIEWER (3D VISIALIZATIONS AND GRAPHS)

2018 - Present

- Upgrade legacy codebase from Qt4 to Qt5 and on the road to Qt6
- 3d visualization with Qt OpenGL, plots with QwtPlot

Fire Integrity Analysis of Flanges (Python, Brilliant, C++)

Diff. petroleum companies

2017 - 2020

1

CREATE 3D PARAMETERIZED SIMULATION MODELS AND ANALYZE THE RESULTS

- Automate the whole process of generating simulation models and run simulations (Python)
- Result analysis and presentation with Python using NumPy and Matplotlib
- Import from and export to Excel using python with xlsxwriter

Rupturing of pipes, High Temperature Material Testing (Python)

ANALYZE EXPERIMENTAL VIDEOS OF PIPES EXPOSED TO FIRE TO

Oil and gas company 2016 - 2017

- Using Python with OpenCV to fetch video file and read each frame
- Analyze each image frames brightness to detect pipe edges

Work Experience_

Petrell ASTrondheim, NorwaySENIOR ENGINEER2012 - Present

- Developing inhouse multiphysics simulation software
- Performing fire-, structural integrity- and CFD simulations with the inhouse softwares Brilliant and VessFire
- Customer support, license

Internships at Petrell, Idéportalen, St. Olavs

Trondheim, Norway 2008 - 2011

Education

NTNU
MASTER OF SCIENCE IN APPLIED PHYSICS
Trondheim, Norway
2006-12

- Master thesis: Modelling of thermal radiation for use in fire simulations (at Petrell)
- Specializing in numerical physics
- Broad background in mathematics, physics, and data science.